Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003.
  - Lowenthal, Max, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Lowenthal, Max: and Alger Hiss, 1995, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Lowenthal, Max: Correspondence, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Lowenthal, Max: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, Jun 7, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 1, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 6, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 6 Bulky 576, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 7, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 8, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 9, Part 1, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 9, Part 2), undated (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Sections 9 and 10), undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 11), undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 12, Part 1), undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 12, Part 2), undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Sections 13 and 14), undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - MacArthur, John: Re: Harpers, 1992-1996, 2002-2003 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Marbury, William, 1976-1978, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Mark, Eduard: Reply from JL re: "Alger Hiss, The Perfect Victim", 2003 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mark, Eduard: Reply from JL re: "Who Was Venona's 'Ales'? Cryptoanalysis and the Hiss Case", 2003 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Marshall Plan, 1997-1999 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Martino, Rose, 1966, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - McDowell, John: Correspondence, Jul 23, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Merillat, Herbert Christopher: Correspondence, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Larry: "Clarence Evan Pickett and the Alger Hiss Case," Typescript, undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Moor, Paul: Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Moore, William: Correspondence, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - The Movie, Typescript, Mar 1998 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Murphy, Robert C.: "The Hiss Case: Insights," Re:, undated, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Murphy, Thomas F.: Correspondence, 1972, 1977-1978 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Murphy, Thomas: "Summation to the Jury: People of the United States v. Alger Hiss" (Plain Talk) Aug 1949 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Musmanno, Michael A.: That Chambers Book: With Comment on Communism, Alger Hiss and the State of Our Times, Pamphlet, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Nation: Articles/Editorials, 1976, 1992, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Nation Institute: "Investigative Reporting after the Cold War," Conference, Moscow State University, Sep 4, 1992-Sep 7, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Nation Institute: Press Reactions to Nation Institute's Cold War Archive Hiss Project, Clippings, Oct 1992-Mar 1993 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee: Correspondence, 1980, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - National Popular Government League: Report on the Illegal Practices of the U.S. Department of Justice, Pamphlet, May 1920 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - National Review: Re: Hiss, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Navasky, Victor: Correspondence, 1978-2001 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Navasky, Victor: Re: Communism, Hiss, 1978, 1996, 2000-2001 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Nedelkoff, Robert: Correspondence, undated, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Nelson, Lawrence J.: Correspondence, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - New Criterion: "Notes and Comments," re: Hiss, Dec 1992 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Newmyer, Jacqueline: "The Vindication of an Innocent Man", 1993 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Newshour with Jim Lehrer: Transcript re: Nixon Tapes, Jan 2, 1997 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Newsweek: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Nezavisimaya Gazeta, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Nixon, Richard: Re: Hiss, undated, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Nixon, Richard: "The Hiss Case: A Lesson for the American People," Speech, Jan 26, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Nixon, Richard: Six Crises, Excerpts, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Nixon's Manipulations in the Hiss-Chambers Case (JL): Typescript, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Handwritten, re: Hiss Books, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oates, Titus: Handwritten Notes re:, undated, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Opinions-Editorials (JL), 1962, 1996, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Osann, H. E.: "The Alger Hiss Case," Correspondence and Typescript, 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Piel, Gerard: Clash of Civilizations, re:, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Pierce, Edward: Re: "Ales", undated, 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Pigman, Ward, 1948, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Political Cartoons: Dreyfus, Hiss, undated, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Political Cartoons: Permission to Reprint, 1970-2000 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Pollack, Louis: U.S.A. v. Carlos Ivan Llera Plaza, Wilfredo Acosta, Victor Rodriguez, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Popkin, Julie: Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Powers, Thomas, Re: Ales, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Prelin, Igor, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Public Citizen Litigation Group: Re: Hiss, May 14, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Public Relations: Re: Hiss, undated, 1986, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Publishers and Agents: Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Quinn, Hannah and James: Correspondence, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Correspondence, Nov 10, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Reuben, William A.: Correspondence, 1970-1989 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Reuben, William A.: Handwritten Notes, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Introduction, undated (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 1, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 2, undated (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 3, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 4, undated (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 6, undated (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 8, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 9, undated (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 10, undated (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 11, undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 12, undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 13, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 14, undated (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 17, undated (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 18, undated (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 21, undated (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 22, undated (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 24, undated (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 25, undated (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 26, Dec 9, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 27, Nov 18, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 28, Apr 16, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 29, Aug 19, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 30, Nov 1, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 31, Nov 24, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 32, Apr 2, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 33, Oct 2000 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 34, undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 36, undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reuben, William A.: Letters to the Editor, 1996, 1999 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 1-5, undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 6-8; 10-13, undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 14-17, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Reuben, William A.: "Whittaker Chambers: An American Hero," Typescript, undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Riptide Communications: Correspondence, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Risen, James: Correspondence, 1993, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Roberts, R. M.: Correspondence, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Roddick, Ellen: Correspondence, Nov 1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Rodell, Fred: "Was Alger Hiss Framed?" (The Progressive), Apr 1952 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Rogers, Bill: Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Romerstein, Herbert: The Venona Secrets, re:, 1992-2001 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg Case, 1951, 1962, 1974-1993 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Rosenwald, Harold: Correspondence, 1972-1977 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Rosenwald, Harold: "In the Matter of Alger Hiss," (Harvard Law School Bulletin), Fall 1975 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Roulhac, George Norman: FBI File, 0000 (Box 19, Folder 19a)
  - Russian Archives: Conference and Trip, 1991-1992, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Russian Archives: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Russian General Says Hiss Was No Spy (JL): Notes and Typescript, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Ryan, Clarke Sylvester, 1950, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Sachs, Nannette Pierson: Correspondence, Dec 23, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Salant, Stephen: Correspondence, 1976-2000 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Salant, Stephen: Writings re: Hiss, undated, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Sanders, Bernard: Correspondence, re: Hiss, Aug 31, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Sandilands, Roger J.: Re: Lauchlin Currie, 1999-2000 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Sayre, Nora, undated, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Scales, Junius: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Schmidt, Maria: Article Re: Hiss, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Schweizer, Werner: "Noel Field: The Fictitious Spy," Typescript, 1996 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Shapiro, Meyer: Re: Hiss, 1948-1949, 1967, 1977-1987 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Shattuck, John H.F.: Letter to the Editor, re: Hiss, Mar 19, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Shaw, Elizabeth: Re: Vincent Shaw, 1986-1987 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Sheehy, Margaret: "Joyous and Sorrowful," Typescript, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Shelley, Alexandra: Article Re: Hiss (East Hampton Star), 1993 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Silvermaster, Nathan Gregory: Handwritten Notes, re:, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Simes, Dmitri, 1993-1994, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Simon Meyer and Son, Inc.: Insurance Policy, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Smith, John Chabot: Correspondence, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Smith, John Chabot: Debate with Allen Weinstein, Opening Statement, Apr 3, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Soviet Historiography on the Hiss Case (JL): Typescript, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Speaker Program, 2000-2003 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Spectator: Correspondence re: Hiss Article, 1996-2000 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Stephens, Robert A. v. William F. Yeomens, undated (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Stevens, Alexander (aka Jay Peters/Alexander Goldberger): Correspondence, May 9, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: "Dealing in Russia" (The American Scholar), 1993 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: "Letter from Serbia" (The American Scholar), 1992 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Stoessel, Frederic: Correspondence, Jul 1975 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Stoskopf, Alan: "The Cold War at Home: The Remarkable Case of Alger Hiss," School Paper, 1983 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Stripling, Robert: Pumpkin Film, 1977, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Summers, Anthony: Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1992-1993, 1997, 1999 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Telephone Tapping, Aug 24, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Toledano, Ralph de: FBI Reports, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 2a)
  - Travel: Trip to Soviet Union, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Bibliographic Notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Borovik, Artiom, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Clippings, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Clippings, Negatives and Positives, 1940-1959 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: British Universities Film and Video Council, 2000-2003 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Chambers, Esther, 1977, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Cooke, Alistair, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Correspondence, re:, 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Correspondence, re:, 1980-1981 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Day, James, Nov 1, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: de Antonio, Emile, 1976-1979 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Direct Cinema, 1992-1999 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Directors Note and Film Transcript, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Endnotes and Film Notes, undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Fariello, Griffin, 1996-2001 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Feinstein, Gussie, 1978-1980 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Frank, Victor Reno, 1977, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Funding/Grants, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1970s (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Handwritten Notes, re:, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Herbert, F. Edward, 1976-1981 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: HUAC, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Inquiries, 1994-2000 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Ladd, Helen, 1977, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Lamb, Edward, 1976, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Levin, Alvin, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Lindau, Alfred M., 1977 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Media Study, Buffalo, 1981-1982 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Mischel, Larry, 1977, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Murtaugh, Edward S., 1977, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Newsreels, undated, 1976-1977, 1983 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Nixon, Richard, 1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Outtakes, 1970-1999 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Photographs, Search for, 1994 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Promotions/Publicity/Distribution, International, 1980-1994 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Promotions/Publicity, National, undated, 1979-1982 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Releases, 1977-1979 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Schmitt, Joseph, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Additions, 2002 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Annotations, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Script Changes, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Shapero, Harold, 1977, 1984 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Shaw, Vincent, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Silk, Lawrence, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Smith, John Chabot, undated, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Sound/Tape Reports, 1976-1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Spencer, Thomas G., 1949, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Strauss, Robert S., Aug 1992 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Stock Footage, undated, 1970s (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Stripling, Robert, 1977, 1980 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Sullivan, William, 1975, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Taylor, Duncan Norton, undated, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Timeline, undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Transcript, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Typescript, p. 1-100, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Typescript, p. 101-214, 1979 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Tytell Typewriter, 1976-1977 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: University of California, Berkeley, Pacific Film Archive, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: von Werner, Robert, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Witt, Nathan, 1976-1977, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Zablodowsky, David, 1977, 1981 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Turner, Kay: Correspondence, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Tytell, Martin: "The $7,500 Typewriter I Built for Alger Hiss" (True Magazine), Aug 1952 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - United Nations: Notes and Typescript, undated, 1965 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - United States Court of Appeals: USA v. Morton Sobell, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: The Film Fund, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: National Endowment for the Humanities, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - USA v. Alger Hiss: The Television Laboratory, 1976-1978 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - United States Department of Agriculture: Agricultural Adjustment Administration, 1935 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Van der Heuvel, Katrina, 1992-1995 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander v. Frank Cass and Co., 2001-2002 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Vassiliev, Alexander v. Frank Cass and Co., 2003 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Venona, 1990s (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Venona: "Ales" Awarded Soviet Decoration, 1953, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Venona Article: Correspondence, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Venona Article: Draft, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Venona Article: Mailing Lists and Public Relations, 2000-2002 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Venona Article: Notes, re:, 2000-2002 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Venona Article: Referees, 2002 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Venona Article: Responses, 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Venona: Bykov, Boris, 1996-1999 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Venona Conference, Oct 3, 1996-Oct 4, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Vinnedge, Harlan: Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Vinnedge, Harlan: "A Second Look at the Hiss Case," Typescript, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Visson, Lynn: Handwritten Notes, re:, Dec 1992 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Von Mehren, Robert: Correspondence, 1975, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Vyshinsky, Andrei Y: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1996, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - W. H. Lowdermilk and Company: HUAC Reprints, re:, May 1962 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Wadleigh, Henry Julian, 1948-1950, 1977, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Washington Post: Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Website: The Alger Hiss Story, 2000-2001 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Website: The Alger Hiss Story, Zip Disc, Nov 11, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Weinstein, Allen, 1970-1999 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Weinstein, Allen: The Haunted Wood, re:, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Weinstein, Allen: Perjury, Re:, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Welles, Summer: Handwritten Notes, re:, Feb 12, 1949 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Were Oppenheimer, Sobell and Hiss Spies?: Typescript and Notes, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, undated, 1952, 1976-1999 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: American Playhouse, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case", 1984 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Alger Hiss Project," First of Three Films, Typescript, undated (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 1 Accusation," Revised Draft, undated (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 2 Confession," First Draft, undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Parts 1 and 2," Revisions, Jul 1983 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: Thames Television, "Concealed Enemies: The Hiss/Chambers Spy Case, Part 3 Investigation," Revisions, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Whitemore, Hugh: "The Trials of Alger Hiss," Treatment, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Why Ales Cannot Be Alger Hiss (JL): Typescript, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Wiener, John: "Compromised Positions" (The Nation), Jan 1993-Feb 1993 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Wiener, John: Re: "Pumpkin Papers", 1990, 1996-1998 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Wines, Michael: Correspondence, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Wood, Sally: Correspondence, Feb 3, 1950 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center for Cold War History: Handwritten Notes re: Hiss, 1992-1993, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Worth, Joan: Correspondence, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Wright, Charles A.: Writings, 1952, 1973, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Younger, Irving: Re: Hiss, 1970s (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Zubok, Vladislav, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 33)
- Series III: Addendum, 1949-1993
  This unprocessed box (1 linear foot) of material is not available for research, pending its reorganization, description, and completion of basic preservation measures.
  - Agnese Nelms Haury Trust / Emil W. Haury Graduate Fellowship Fund, 1991-1992 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Anne [Professor]: Correspondence, 1976, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, John: Correspondence, 1954-1960 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Lowenthal, John: Correspondence, 1971-1993 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letter to "Mother", undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letter to Mr. and Mrs. John Wolf [from Paris], Aug 15, 1949 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Lowenthal, John: Letters to Lowenthal Family [from Paris], Jul 1949-Sep 1949 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - "More on Whittaker Chambers and NYPL" ( Research Libraries Bulletin; vol. 5, no. 3), 1993 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - The Trials of Alger Hiss [film brochure], c. 1980 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - "Vindication for Alger Hiss" ( Rochester Chronicle), Nov 18, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Gray Panthers [2 posters], 1982; undated (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - U.S. Troops Out Now [poster], undated (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss"(London Film Festival) [poster], 1980 (Box MSXOS002, Folder 1)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss" [poster], [1980] (Flat-file 1, Drawer 14)
  - "The Trials of Algiers Hiss" (92nd St Y) [poster], [1980] (Flat-file 1, Drawer 14)
- Series IV: Unprocessed Materials
  - Unprocessed Materials (Box 25-33)